(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-03T00:36:42.925682",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
皆様、
Everyone,
本日は綺々羅々ヴィヴィ生誕祭2026にお越しくださいまして
thank you very much for coming to Kirara Vivi's Birthday Live 2026 today!
誠にありがとうございます！
Thank you so very much!
開演に先立ちまして、
Prior to the start of the show,
皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
we would like to share a few requests and announcements.
当配信は一部収録もございますが、
While portions of this stream are pre-recorded,
生配信部分もございますので、
there are live parts as well,
いーっぱいコメントやポストをして、
so please leave lots of comments and posts,
たーっくさん盛り上げてください！
and get totally hyped up!
みんな、コメントも見えてるよー！
Everyone, I can see your comments too!
当配信のハッシュタグは、
The hashtag for this stream is
「#ヴィヴィ生誕祭2026」です。
"#ViviBirthday2026".
ライブの感想など、
Please share your thoughts on the live show,
SNSでたくさんポストしてください！
and post lots on social media!
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどによる
Taking photos during the show with cameras or smartphones
写真撮影は大歓迎です！
is more than welcome!
たくさんポストして盛り上げてくださると、
I'd be super happy if you post a lot
めっちゃ嬉しいです！
and build up the excitement!
それでは、開演まで
And now, until the show begins,
今しばらくお待ちください！
please wait just a little longer!
皆様！
Everyone!
本日は、綺々羅々ヴィヴィ生誕祭2026にお越しくださいまして、
Thank you all so much for coming to Kikirara Vivi Birthday Festival 2026 today,
誠にありがとうございます！
thank you from the bottom of my heart!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Prior to the show's start, I have a few requests and announcements for everyone.
当配信は、一部収録もございますが、生配信部分もございますので、
This stream includes some pre-recorded parts as well as live portions,
いっぱいコメントやポストをして、たーっくさん盛り上げてください！
so please leave lots of comments and posts to make it super exciting!
コメントも全部見えてるよー！
I can see all your comments, too!
当配信のハッシュタグは、「#ヴィヴィ生誕祭2026」です。
The hashtag for this stream is '#ViviBirthdayFestival2026'.
ライブの感想など、SNSでめーっちゃたくさんポストしてください！
Please post tons of your thoughts on the concert on social media!
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどによる写真撮影は...
During the show, taking photos with cameras or smartphones is...
大歓迎です！
more than welcome!
たくさんポストして盛り上げてくださいますと、ヴィヴィ大歓喜です！
If you post a lot and hype things up, Vivi will be overjoyed!
皆さん！ヴィヴィと楽しむ準備、できてますかー？
Everyone! Are you ready to have fun with Vivi?
おい！ヴィヴィめっちゃ緊張してるよー！
Hey! Vivi is super nervous!
みんな震えるヴィヴィの膝を支えてくれ！ヴィヴィ口も回らんなってきた。
Everyone, support Vivi's trembling knees! My tongue is getting all tangled up, too.
でも、ヴィヴィにメロメロになる準備、できてますかー？
But are you ready to fall head over heels for Vivi?
あ、あ、そっか。みんな、もう、でも、すでにヴィヴィにメロメロか！
Ah, ah, I see. You guys are already head over heels for Vivi anyway!
今日はアイドル全開のヴィヴィを目に焼き付けてな！
Make sure to burn this full-on idol Vivi into your eyes today!
たーっくさん可愛いって言ってー！
Tell me I'm cute lots and lots!
可愛い？
Am I cute?
知ってるー！
I know~!
それでは開演まで今しばらくお待ちください！
Well then, please wait just a little longer until the show begins!
うーん 何だろうな もう本当にこの私がいるのに
Hmm, what is it? Even though I'm right here,
誰よりも君のことを想ってる人が こんなにも近くにいるんだけどな
the person who thinks of you more than anyone is so close to you.
よし こうとなったら そろりそろりと参ります！
Alright, if that's how it's gonna be, I'll make my move slowly but surely!
シュービードゥービー Are you ready? Go!
Shooby-dooby, are you ready? Go!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ねえ この後 予定とかあるの？
Hey, do you have any plans after this?
帰り道も一緒だし どう？
We walk home the same way, so how about it?
そう言えば今日 髪の分け目変えたんだよ
Come to think of it, I parted my hair differently today.
気づいてる？
Did you notice?
あー あの手この手使ってもあんまり実感ないな どうなんだろう これ相談乗るべきなのかな？
Ah, trying this and that doesn't really sink in. Wonder how it is, should I give advice on this?
って何で何で他なんだよ！私の方なんじゃないのかな？
Wait, why is it someone else?! Shouldn't it be about me?
えーい 知らーん！
Ugh, whatever, I don't care!
周りに目移りしないでよ
Don't let your eyes wander around;
私だって
look at me!
I want you なんとか少しでも一緒に居たいんだけど
I want you, I want to be together with you even a little longer,
I need you ねえねえそろそろ気づいちゃってるんじゃない？
I need you, hey, hey, aren't you starting to realize it by now?
ぎゅっとして ねえ
Hold me tight, please...
もう こっち向いて！
Jeez, look at me!
茶化さんとテレパシー だんだん噛み合う
Without teasing, telepathy gradually clicks in place,
特大バンバン撃ち抜かれる L・O・V・E
shot right through with extra-large bangs: L-O-V-E!
ドキドキハートがテンパシッてる
My throbbing heart is freaking out,
もういっそのこと君と永遠に
might as well stay with you forever.
エンドレスラブ 雨キッス 感情飛ばして満たす
Endless love, rainy kiss, letting emotions fly to fill it,
愛トキシック マゼンタ ほら目を合わせてよ
love toxic magenta, look, meet my eyes.
指先なぞって教えてあげる
Tracing my fingertips, I'll let you know
恋と気づくまでの カウントダウンラブ バン！
the countdown to realizing it's love, love—bang!
目と目合ってクラクラリ
Our eyes meet, making me dizzy,
いつでも準備は出来てる
I'm ready anytime.
触れ合えば もうクラクラ
When we touch, I'm already spinning...
つまり 私だけ見ててね (ねっ)
In other words, just keep your eyes on me, okay? (Right?)
絶対！
Definitely!
Yeah! (はい はい)
Yeah! (Hai, hai!)
朝起きてすぐから 決まるモチベーション
My motivation is set right from the moment I wake up.
視覚 聴覚 言語の3つで 人の印象は決定します
A person's impression is decided by three things: visual, auditory, and verbal.
余すことなくチェック 今日も可愛いでしょう？
Checking everything thoroughly—I look cute today too, don't I?
Hey Hey Hurry Up! ショータイム さあ君だけの ワンタイム
Hey, hey, hurry up! Showtime! Come on, it's a one-time just for you!
1対1 一期一会に感謝と誠意を感じる エナジー
One-on-one, once-in-a-lifetime energy, filled with gratitude and sincerity!
他には居やへん 私が可愛いから 自然とご褒美よ
There's no one else like me; because I'm so cute, it's naturally a reward!
ただ一向 あんまり実感ないな どうなんだろう？ これ決定打？
But still, it doesn't quite feel real. How is it? Is this the deciding blow?
正味問題 振り向いてくれたら いいさ いいさ 屁でも問題ない！
Truth is, as long as you look my way, it's fine, it's fine, no problem at all!
えへへ、まったく不器用なんだから... 少しは素直になって... えーっ！これじゃない気がするー！
Ehehe, you're so clumsy... Just be a little more honest... Wait! I feel like this isn't it!
3 2 1 GO! 特等席 最前線から 見ててほしいな
3, 2, 1, GO! I want you to watch from the front row, the special seat!
3 2 1 GO! ねえねえ ぼちぼち分かっちゃってるんじゃない？
3, 2, 1, GO! Hey, hey, haven't you started to figure it out by now?
そう きゅんとしてね！
That's right, let your heart skip a beat!
もう、勝ちに来てよ！
Geez, come and win me over!
ちゃっかりとした君に ピースサイン 駆け引きの連鎖
Flashing a peace sign at the shrewd you, a chain of subtle games.
また気づけば狂う時間 注いで
Pouring in time that goes crazy again before I know it...
ドキドキ ハートがテレパシーしてる
My pounding heart is sending telepathy.
もう いっそのこと 私 永遠に
I'd rather just, forever and ever...
Happiness Love and Kiss 合言葉で示す 愛
Happiness, love and kiss, love expressed through a password!
アタフタしたって ほらまた 眠れないよ
Even if I get flustered, look, I can't sleep again!
指折り数えて 教えてあげる
I'll count on my fingers and tell you...
恋に気づくまでの カウントダウン
The countdown until you realize it's love!
うー、そうだなぁ... 灯台下暗しって言葉が合うのかなぁ...？ 漫画の無神経主人公感！って思いますよねぇ？
Hmm, let's see... Maybe "darkness at the foot of the lighthouse" fits? It really feels like an oblivious manga protagonist, don't you think?
もう我慢ならない！ 分かりやすく参ります！
I can't take it anymore! I'll make it crystal clear!
Shoo-be-doo-be Are you ready? GO!
Yeah! (はい はい)
Yeah! (Hai, hai!)
Woh-oh-oh-oh (はい はい)
Woh-oh-oh-oh (Hai, hai!)
Uh-oh...
ちょっと強がりで 照れくさくて
Acting a little tough, feeling so shy...
でも 止まれないの
But I just can't stop.
いつかを 待ち続けたよ
I've kept waiting for that someday...
私を見ててね
So keep looking at me, okay?
好き。
I like you.
Endless Love and Kiss 感情と言葉で満たす 愛
Endless love and kiss, love filled with emotions and words!
1 2 Ready Start ほら 目を合わせてよ
One, two, ready, start! Come on, meet my eyes!
指先なぞって 教えてあげる
Tracing my fingertips, I'll teach you...
恋と気づくまでの カウントダウン (Bang!)
The countdown until you realize it's love! (Bang!)
目と目合わせて クラクラになり
Locking eyes and getting dizzy...
いつでも準備は できてる
I'm ready at any moment.
触れ合えば もうグラグラに
If we touch, I'll be totally unsteady...
今すぐ 抱きしめて
Hold me tight right now!
私だけ見ててね
Keep your eyes only on me, okay?
絶対！
Definitely!
Yeah! (はい はい)
Yeah! (Hai, hai!)
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
今日は どこに行こうかな
Where should we go today?
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
ふたりの思い出を 重ねて
Stacking up memories of the two of us.
[曲名：ねぇ / 作詞・作曲：中田ヤスタカ]
[Song: Nee / Lyrics & Composition: Yasutaka Nakata]
まぶしくって 目がさめた日は
On days when the bright light wakes me up,
ちょっとだけ 気持ちいい 眠いけど
It feels kind of nice, though I'm still sleepy...
せっかくだし
And since we have this chance...
キミはもう 起きているかな
I wonder if you're already awake?
今日の予定を かいてみたての
Freshly writing down today's plans...
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
今日は どこに行こうかな
Where should we go today?
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
ふたりの思い出を 重ねて
Stacking up memories of the two of us.
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
明日は どこに行こうかな
Where should we go tomorrow?
キミといると 行き先は どこも特別に変わるの
When I'm with you, any destination turns into somewhere special.
信号が 青に変われば
Once the traffic light turns green,
あとは この先に 待ってるのは 広い海
All that's waiting ahead is the wide, open sea.
海岸を沿うように駆ける
Driving along the coast,
いつもの音楽を BGMにして
with our usual music as the background soundtrack.
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 今日はどこに行こうかな
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where should we go today?
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ふたりの思い出を重ねて
Hey, hey, hey, hey, stacking up our memories together,
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 明日はどこに行こうかな
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where should we go tomorrow?
キミといると 行き先はどこも特別に変わるの
When I'm with you, any destination turns into somewhere special.
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 今日はどこに行こうかな
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where should we go today?
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ふたりの思い出を重ねて
Hey, hey, hey, hey, stacking up our memories together,
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ 明日はどこに行こうかな
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where should we go tomorrow?
キミといると 行き先はどこも特別に変わるの
When I'm with you, any destination turns into somewhere special.
ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ ねぇ
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
IRIS OUT
だめ だめ だめ
No, no, no,
脳みその中から やめろ馬鹿とわめくモラリティ
morality screams from inside my brain, "Stop it, you idiot!"
だりぃ ベタベタに 半端なくラブと煌めき 浮き足立つフィロソフィー
Tiresomely sticky, restless philosophy with insane love and sparkle.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い 何がし頬に触れるくらい
That look from upturned eyes is fatally cute, close enough to brush my cheek.
ばらまく乱視 気づけば当事者 この世に生まれた君が悪い
Scattering astigmatism, suddenly I'm caught up in it—it's your fault for being born.
やたらとしんどい恋煩い バラバラになる頭とこの身体
An excessively agonizing lovesickness, tearing my head and body apart,
けど 目から「アイラブユー」顔引き攣らせて アイリスアウト
yet, sending "I love you" from my eyes with a twitching face—Iris Out!
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
肋の奥 ザラメが溶けて ゲロになりそう
Deep inside my ribs, coarse sugar melts, making me feel like throwing up.
パッと ドッと バッと開いて ぼろ雑巾になって
Bursting open suddenly, worn out like a tattered rag,
今 この世で君だけ大正解
right now in this world, only you are the absolute answer.
だりぃ だりぃ だりぃ だりぃ
So tedious, so tedious, so tedious, so tedious,
so tedious, so tedious, so tedious, so tedious!
ひっくり返っても勝ち目ない 君のキロメートル適応外
No chance of winning no matter what; out of range of your kilometers,
四つ巴の手は黒しかない 喝采あげ放題
backed into a corner with only dark cards to play, freely showering praises.
君が笑顔で放ったアブラカタブラで デコにスティグマ もう言い訳できない
With the Abracadabra you cast with a smile, a stigma on my forehead—no more excuses.
ズン 矢を射して ズン 貫いて ズン ここ弱点
*Thud* pierce it with an arrow, *thud* run it through, *thud* that's my weak spot!
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い 何がし頬に触れるくらい
That look from upturned eyes is fatally cute, close enough to brush my cheek.
ばらまく乱視 気づけば当事者 この世に生まれた君が悪い
Scattering astigmatism, suddenly I'm caught up in it—it's your fault for being born.
パチモンでもいい 何でもいい 今君と名付いてるすべて欲しい
A counterfeit is fine, anything is fine, I want everything bearing your name right now,
けど 目から「アイラブユー」顔引き攣らせて アイリスアウト
yet, sending "I love you" from my eyes with a twitching face—Iris Out!
アイリスアウト
Iris Out!
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
肋の奥 ザラメが溶けて ゲロになりそう
Deep inside my ribs, coarse sugar melts, making me feel like throwing up.
パッと ドッと バッと開いて ぼろ雑巾になって
Bursting open suddenly, worn out like a tattered rag,
今 この世で君だけ大正解
right now in this world, only you are the absolute answer.
だりぃ だりぃ だりぃ だりぃ
So tedious, so tedious, so tedious, so tedious,
だりぃ だりぃ だりぃ だりぃ！
so tedious, so tedious, so tedious, so tedious!
Wow...
はーい、みんなー！
Hi, everyone!
挨拶します！
Let's do our greeting!
せーの！
Ready, set...
う〜〜〜ん、ビビッ！
Mmm... Bibi!
いつもキラキラな、綺羅星びびでーす！
Always sparkling, I'm Kiraboshi Bibi!
わー！
Yay!
みんなー！ここまで3曲続けて披露させていただきましたー！
Everyone! I've just performed three songs in a row for you!
『Countdown Love』、『ねぇ、アイリスアウト』、それぞれびび、どうやった？
In "Countdown Love" and "Nee, Iris Out", how was Bibi?
可愛くて、セクシーで、ヘルシーやった？
Was I cute, sexy, and healthy?
はい！まあね、見たらわかるヘルシー・セクシー・キューティーのびびなんですけれども、
Yes! Well, as you can see, I'm the healthy, sexy, and cute Bibi, but...
あ！そして！みんな！今、情報が入りました！
Oh! And everyone! I just got some news!
トレンド2位だってー！
We're trending at number two!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
でもでも、びび、1位になりたいなー、1位になりたいなー！
But still, Bibi wants to reach number one... I really want to be number one!
ぜひですね、今日のハッシュタグは「#びび生誕祭2026」で、
So please, use today's hashtag #BibiSeitansai2026,
もうめちゃめちゃたくさんポストしまくってください！
and post as much as you can!
可愛いびびをいっぱいスクショしてなー！
Take lots of screenshots of cute Bibi, okay?
はい！そして、今回のですね、ライブのコンセプトは、
Yes! And the concept for this live show is...
まあ先ほども言ったように、キューティー、ヘルシー、セクシーの3つになってますー！
Just like I mentioned earlier, it's the three themes: Cute, Healthy, and Sexy!
はい！雰囲気もね、テーマに合わせて、まあ、変わってたんですけど、この舞台。みんな気づいてたかなー？
Yes! The atmosphere of this stage has also been changing to match the theme. Did everyone notice?
はい、このあともね、楽曲もテーマによって変化していくので、お楽しみにー！
Yes, from here on, the songs will also change according to the theme, so look forward to it!
あー、こんなでっかいステージに立てて、びび幸せ者やー！
Ah, standing on such a huge stage makes Bibi so happy!
みんなありがとうー！
Thank you, everyone!
それでは、次はゲストパートです！
And now, next is the guest section!
ゲストパートは収録なのですが、
The guest part is pre-recorded, but...
あんなことやこんなことも、しちゃいますよー！
We'll be doing this, and that, and all sorts of things!
もう、いやらしい！
Oh, so naughty!
胸ぐらを掴まれて 強烈なパンチを
Grabbed by the collar, I took a heavy punch
食らってよろけて 肩を並べ蹲った
And staggered back, crouching down shoulder to shoulder
予報通りの雨にお前はにやけて
In the forecasted rain, you grinned
傷口が綺麗になるなんて嘘をつく
Lying that it would wash our wounds clean
いつも口喧嘩さえ うまく出来ないくせして
Even though you can't even hold your own in an argument,
冴えない冗談言うなよ
Don't tell such lame jokes
あまりのつまらなさに 目が潤んだ
They're so unfunny it brought tears to my eyes
何度も青あざだらけで 涙を
Covered in bruises again and again, tears
流して 流して
Flow and flow
不安定な心を 肩に預け合いながら
As we lean our unstable hearts on each other's shoulders
腐り切ったバッドエンドに抗う
We fight against this rotten bad ending
何故だろう 喜びよりも心地よい痛みが
Why is it that this pain feels more comforting than joy,
ずっしりと響いて
Resonating so heavily deep inside?
濡れた服に 舌打ちしながら
Clicking our tongues at our soaked clothes,
腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
We look at each other's swollen faces and laugh
土砂降りの夜に
On this night in the pouring rain,
誓ったリベンジ
We swore our revenge
胸ぐらを掴み返して 反撃のパンチを
Grabbing them back by the collar, ready to throw
繰り出すくらいじゃなきゃ お前の隣には立てないから
A counter punch, or else I can't stand beside you
相手が何であれ日和らない 何度伸されても諦めない
No matter who the opponent is, I won't back down; no matter how many times I'm knocked down, I won't give up
忘れるな 忘れるなと言い聞かせ 続けてきたのに
I kept telling myself, "Don't forget, never forget," and yet...
やり直して しくじって やり過ごして 離れたいよ
Starting over, messing up, letting things pass, wanting to get away
やり直して しくじって やり過ごして 肩を貸して
Starting over, messing up, letting things pass, lend me a shoulder
Ah...
あぁ 傘はいらないから
Ah, I don't need an umbrella,
言葉を一つくれないか
So won't you give me some words instead?
ぬるい優しさではなく
Not lukewarm kindness,
弱音に侵された 胸の奥を 抉るような言葉を
But words that will gouge out the depths of my heart infested with weakness
何度も青あざだらけで 涙を
Covered in bruises again and again, tears...
流して 流して
Shedding them, shedding them,
不安定な心を肩に預け合いながら
Leaning our unstable hearts on each other's shoulders,
腐りきったバッドエンドに抗う
We fight against this rotten bad ending.
なぜだろう 喜びよりも心地よい
Why is it that, even more comforting than joy,
痛み ズシリと響いて
The pain echoes heavily inside?
濡れた服に舌打ちしながら
Tutting at our soaking wet clothes,
腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
We look at our swollen faces and laugh.
土砂降りの夜に
On this drenching night,
囚われの日々に
In these captive days,
問いかけるように光った瞳の中で
In those eyes that shone as if questioning,
誓ったリベンジ
We swore our revenge.
あたしヴァンパイア いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
I'm a vampire, is it okay? Can I bite you?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて悪い子だね
Saying "No more, no more"—what a bad child.
試したいな いっぱいで吐きたい まだ絶対いけるよ
I want to test it, fill up till I throw up, I can definitely keep going!
最低最高 ずっと行き来してる 甘くなる不安の果実
Going back and forth between the lowest and highest, the fruit of anxiety grows sweeter.
No more 発達 嫉妬息をしても 要らないだけ 煩いだけ
No more growth, even if you sigh with jealousy, it's just unwanted, just annoying.
誰かと居れば それはタラレバ
Being with someone is just a "what if."
強がってたって 気持ちにゃ逆らえない
Acting tough, but you can't go against your feelings.
離れていても 感じてるエモ
Even when apart, I feel the emotion.
繋がって確かめたら 死ねるかも
If we connect and confirm it, I might die.
いいもん 悲しいもん 切ないもん
It's fine, it's sad, it's painful...
君のすべてを喰らうまで
Until I devour everything of yours!
絶叫
Scream!
あたしヴァンパイア いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
I'm a vampire, is it okay? Can I bite you?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて悪い子だね
Saying "No more, no more"—what a bad child.
試したいな いっぱいで吐きたい まだ絶対いけるよ
I want to test it, fill up till I throw up, I can definitely keep going!
また求めちゃって また喰らっちゃって これやんなる感じ
Wanting it again, devouring it again, this sick feeling...
泣いて忘れちゃって 初めまして
Crying and forgetting it all—nice to meet you!
あたしヴァンパイア 愛情をください まだ絶対いけるよ
I'm a vampire, give me love, I can definitely keep going!
あたしヴァンパイア まずはこっちおいで
I'm a vampire, first come over here.
内緒の想い 洗いざらい
All of your secret thoughts, laid completely bare.
吐き出したなら まさにバカリ 割り切れないけど あんまりじゃない
Once spit out, it's nothing but a show, I can't accept it, but isn't that too much?
そっと朝まで通せんぼ
Gently blocking your path until morning.
踏み暮らすような 我慢もただ 欲張ってまたチャンスを逃すのだ
Stomping through life, endurance is just being greedy and missing chances again.
嫌味も哀憐も 叶えたいけど 重なって押しつぶされちゃうのかも
Sarcasm and pity, I want to fulfill them, but piling up, they might crush me.
いいもん 悲しいもん 切ないもん
It's fine, it's sad, it's painful...
君のすべてを喰らうまで
Until I devour everything of yours!
いいじゃん 悲しいじゃん 気持ちいいじゃん
Isn't it fine? Isn't it sad? Doesn't it feel good?
溺れるまで 勝手になるね
Until we drown, I'll do as I please!
絶叫
Scream!
あたしヴァンパイア いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
I'm a vampire, is it okay? Can I bite you?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて悪い子だね
Saying "No more, no more"—what a bad child.
試したいな いっぱいで吐きたい まだ絶対いけるよ
I want to test it, fill up till I throw up, I can definitely keep going!
君もヴァンパイア いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
You're a vampire too, go ahead and bite me.
「もう無理もう無理」だって言わせてほしい
I want you to make me say "No more, no more."
君以外では 絶対にいけない
With anyone but you, I definitely can't reach it.
ほら絶賛 狂わせてよ
Come on, drive me delightfully insane!
また求めちゃって また喰らっちゃって 今何回目？
Wanting it again, devouring it again, what time is it now?
星が見えるような 泡の中で
Inside the bubbles where stars seem visible...
延長をください まだ絶対いけるよ
Give me an extension, I can definitely keep going!
君もヴァンパイア まずはこっちおいで
You're a vampire too, first come over here.
ななななな ななななな ななななな ななななな
Na-na-na-na-na, na-na-na-na-na, na-na-na-na-na, na-na-na-na-na...
絶対いけるよ
We can definitely make it!
ねえ あたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
君が一人 知ってるの 知ってるよ
That you're alone, I know it, I know.
ビクンビクン震えてさ 声もダダ漏れなんだわ
Twitching and trembling, your voice is completely leaking out.
正直に言っちゃえよ
Just say it honestly!
バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ 聞いてんの？
It's totally obvious, so confess! Are you listening?
普通普通恥ずかしい みんな隠しているだけ むふっ
It's normal, normal to be embarrassed, everyone is just hiding it. Hehe.
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君が...
Hey, I know, that you're...
君が一人涙してるの 知ってるよ
I know that you're crying all alone.
くすんくすんへこんでさ 弱音吐くからいいんじゃない？
Sniffling and feeling down, isn't it okay to show your weakness?
朝が来るまで一騎当千 もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
A match for a thousand until morning comes; cry even more, I'll embrace it all again and again.
もう我慢しないで いっぱい出してね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out, okay?
んー、まっ！
Mmh, mwah!
お願い君が欲しいの 慰めさせて
Please, I want you; let me console you,
Shake shake 愛の才能で
Shake, shake, with the talent of love.
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう 濡れていたい ねえいいでしょ？
If you don't cry for me, I'll wither away; I want to stay wet, hey, isn't that fine?
舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to lick it all away and drink it dry.
んー、まっ！
Mmh, mwah!
お願い君が欲しいの 手折り散らして
Please, I want you; pluck and scatter me away,
シック・ラップなんて最高ね
Chic wrap is the absolute best, isn't it?
分けてくれなきゃ 君の痛い 感じてたい ねえいいでしょ？
If you don't share it with me... I want to feel your pain, hey, isn't that fine?
吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to suck it out and save you.
痛みたい 痛みたい 君の中
I want to hurt, I want to hurt inside of you...
痛みたい 痛みたい...
I want to hurt, I want to hurt...
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君が一人悔しがってるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know; I know that you're feeling frustrated all alone.
ずきゅんずきゅん高鳴るじゃん 君は推すことをやめない
My heart goes thump-thump racing, you won't stop supporting me.
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君はできる子 知ってるよ
Hey, I know; I know you're a capable one.
辛い時は弱いぐらいで丁度いい あたしそれでも好きだよ
When it hurts, being a little weak is just right; I still love you all the same.
んー、まっ！
Mmh, mwah!
お願い君が欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ
Please, I want you; call out my name,
いつだって愛に参上
Always arriving in the name of love.
君は一人だ だから歌 独りじゃない
You're all alone—that's why a song! You're not alone.
もういいでしょ？ ソロプレイはおしまいなんだってば
That's enough, right? I'm telling you, solo play is over.
君がやめるときも あたしそばにいるわ
Even when you want to quit, I'll be by your side.
いつも今も見守っているわ そうよ
Always, even now, I'm watching over you; that's right,
怖くないのよ
There's nothing to fear!
んー、まっ！
Mmh, mwah!
お願い君が欲しいの 慰めさせて
Please, I want you; let me console you,
Shake shake 愛の talents で
Shake, shake, with the talent of love.
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう 濡れていたい ねえいいでしょ？
If you don't cry for me, I'll wither away; I want to stay wet, hey, isn't that fine?
舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to lick it all away and drink it dry.
んー、まっ！
Mmh, mwah!
お願い君が欲しいの 手折り散らして
Please, I want you; pluck and scatter me away,
シック・ラップなんて最高ね
Chic wrap is the absolute best, isn't it?
分けてくれなきゃ 君の痛い 感じてたい 覗いてたい
If you don't share it with me... I want to feel your pain, I want to peek inside.
吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to suck it out and save you.
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君が一人涙してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know; I know that you're crying all alone.
くすんくすんへこんでさ 弱音吐くからいいんじゃない？
Sniffling and feeling down, isn't it okay to show your weakness?
朝が来るまで一騎当千 もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
A match for a thousand until morning comes; cry even more, I'll embrace it all again and again.
もう我慢しないで 出してってば
Don't hold back anymore, let it out, I said!
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try asking me for something...
おねがいダーリン / 作詞・作曲：ナナホシ管弦楽団
[Onegai Darling / Music & Lyrics: Nanahoshi Orchestra]
ダーリン あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you don't listen to a single thing I say!
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も
Even with cigarettes and alcohol, which I told you so much to quit,
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず
Every day two packs and seven cans without missing a single day;
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても
Even if your liver gets ruined and you kick the bucket,
看病してあげないんだから
I'm not going to nurse you!
ああ言えばこう言う てこでもきかない
You always have a comeback, completely stubborn and unyielding;
あなたのハートは真っ黒です
Your heart is pitch black!
行きたいとこからやりたいことまで 決めてるくせしてだんまりさん
Even though you've decided everything from where to go to what to do, you stay silent!
ねえ そんなの馬鹿みたいじゃない？
Hey, isn't that just ridiculous?
そうじゃない？ じゃない？ じゃない？ (言いたいことあるならさっさと言えば？)
Isn't it? Right? Right? (If you have something to say, why don't you just spit it out?)
いつも思わせぶりな感じで
Always acting so suggestive,
察してほしい感じで
Acting like you want me to take the hint,
わざと口にしないの ずるくない？
Not saying it on purpose—isn't that unfair?
馬鹿じゃないの？
Are you an idiot?
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは形のないもの
Please, Darling, look and listen; what I want is something without a shape.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて 覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
I won't make fun of you, look and listen; peek deep into my eyes,
まっすぐ見つめて
Gaze straight at me.
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try asking me for something...
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all!
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに
Even though I've gazed at you so devotedly,
今ではすっかり知らんぷり
Now you just play completely dumb!
ていうかそれって胡座かいてるだけなんじゃないですかぶっちゃけ
I mean, frankly speaking, aren't you just resting on your laurels?
舌先三寸 あなたのお陰で 私のハートはボロボロです
Smooth-talking—thanks to you, my heart is utterly tattered!
つれない時はつれないし
When you're cold, you're so cold,
そっちが中々言い出さないから いつも私が舵取りじゃん
And since you rarely speak up, I'm always the one taking the lead!
ねえ なんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない？
Hey, doesn't this seem kind of ridiculous?
そうじゃない？ じゃない？ じゃない？
Isn't it? Right? Right?
どこか足元見てる感じで
Like you're looking down on me somehow,
値踏みされてる感じで (なにそれ)
Like you're sizing me up— (What's with that?)
駆け引きやら勝ち負けじゃなくない？
Isn't love not about mind games and winning or losing?
そういうめんどくさいことしてるから めんどくさいことになるんだよ
Because you do such annoying things, it turns into an annoying mess!
寡黙なダーリン ねえ聞いて 切なさは飾りじゃないのよ
Silent Darling, hey, listen; this pain isn't just for decoration.
よそ見しないで 逃げないで 触ってよ 心の奥の方
Don't look away, don't run away; touch deep into my heart.
一瞬のことじゃない
This isn't just for a fleeting moment.
おねだりしてはくれないの？
Won't you ask me for something?
言葉に出来ない臆病さは 健気さではないのよ (ほんとそれな)
Cowardice that can't be put into words isn't devotion, you know. (Seriously, so true.)
甘えてないで 口に出してよ
Stop acting spoiled, and say it out loud!
もう！ちゃんとこっち向いてったら！
Jeez! Look over this way already!
おねがいダーリン 見て聞いて
Please darling, look and listen!
欲しいのは形のないもの
What I want is something without shape!
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて
I won't make fun of you, look and listen!
覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
Peek deep into my eyes!
寡黙なダーリン 寝てないで
Silent darling, don't keep sleeping!
暴いてよ 私の素顔を
Uncover my true feelings!
おねがいダーリン そばにいて
Please darling, stay by my side!
触らせて 心の奥の方
Let me touch deep into your heart!
真っ直ぐ見つめて
Gaze straight at me...
おねだりしてみてほしいの
...and try begging me for it!
おー！
Oh!
おねがいダーリン
Please, darling!
うわー！ぺこら先輩！
Whoa! Pekora-senpai!
聞いたよー！
I heard!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いやーっと二人で歌えてめっちゃ嬉しいです！
I'm so happy the two of us finally got to sing together!
いや、まずはこれを言わせろッピ、ビビ。
No, let me say this first, Bibi.
ん？
Hmm?
お誕生日おめぺこ！
Happy birthday-peko!
やったー！あははは！
Yay! Ahaha!
おめぺこ！
Happy birthday-peko!
出た、おめぺこ！
There it is, "ome-peko"!
え、去年さあ、ビビ凸待ちしたじゃないですか。
Hey, last year, I hosted a call-in stream, right?
した？
Did you?
え、な、覚えてないんかい！おーい！
Wha- You don't remember?! Hey!
え、え、ぺこら行った？
Wait, did Pekora go?
来てくれたやーん！
You came!
あ、行ったよね！行ったぺこだよね！
Ah, I did, right?! I went-peko, didn't I?!
突然サプライズでマネージャーさんから「ぺこらさんからプレゼント預かってます」って。
Suddenly, as a surprise, the manager told me, "I have a present for you from Pekora-san."
あ、そうだ！ああ、思い出した思い出した！
Ah, that's right! Ah, I remember, I remember!
思い出した？
You remembered?
おめでとう！今年はほら、
Congrats! This year, look...
おい、忘れてんじゃんか！
Hey, you totally forgot, didn't you?!
3Dで来たよー！
...I came in 3D!
おーい！
Hey!
ビビ今日さ、そのプレゼントつけてきたのにさ、気づいてへんなーって思ってさー。
Bibi wore that present today, but I was thinking, "She hasn't noticed it at all..."
あー！いや、つけてたよ！ねえ！つけてた！
Ah! No, you were wearing it! Look! You were wearing it!
これ、ヘアクリップつけてた、蝶々入り。
I was wearing this butterfly hair clip!
いや、分かってたよ。いや、つけてくれてたなーっていう風に思ってたけど、ほら恥ずかしくてやっぱ言えなかった。
No, I knew! I thought, "Oh, she's wearing it," but, you know, I was too shy to say it!
嘘つけ！嘘つけ！
Liar! Such a liar!
いやいや、でもそれぐらい嬉しかったんですよ。だから去年に引き続きね、
No, no, but that's how happy I was! So continuing from last year...
今年もこうやってぺこら先輩におめでとうって言ってもらえて、嬉しい！ビビ大歓喜！
Having Pekora-senpai wish me a happy birthday again this year makes me so happy! Bibi is thrilled!
いや、ぺこらもね、ビビちゃんとさ、二人で歌うのってなかなかないぺこだからね。
Well, Pekora rarely gets to sing just the two of us with Bibi-chan-peko,
観てるね、人も多分嬉しいぺこなんじゃないかなーって思ってね。
so I thought the people watching would probably be happy too-peko!
ほんまに！ぺこビビ最強！
Really! Peko-Bibi is the strongest!
最強！最強！
Strongest! Strongest!
何が最強じゃー！
What do you mean "strongest"?!
ぺこマリ最強！ぺこマリ最強！
Peko-Mari is the strongest! Peko-Mari is the strongest!
来たー！
She's here!
ばばあ狩りに来いや！ばばあ狩りに来いや！
Come on, do some hag hunting! Hunt this hag!
年中無休！
Open 365 days a year!
年中無休のばばあ狩り！
Year-round hag hunting!
あれ？あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh? Huh?
形勢逆転？
Have the tables turned?
形勢逆転...
The tables have turned...
追いやられて持っていかれた...
I got cornered and outdone...
ビビ、何歳になったの？
Bibi, how old did you turn?
いや、ビビはぴちぴちの22ちゃい！
Bibi is a fresh and youthful 22 years old!
22ちゃい、あれ？前まで何歳だったんだっけ？
22 years old? Huh? How old were you before?
あ、22ちゃいです！
Ah, 22 years old!
やかましいわ！てめぇ！
Shut your mouth, you!
何が22ちゃいじゃ！
What do you mean "22 years old"?!
黙れよ！三十路の世界来いよ、お前も！
Shut up! Come join the world of turning thirty, you too!
いや、歳とらないんで。
No, I don't age.
三十路にならない？
You won't turn thirty?
いや、「鬼にならないか」じゃないよ！
Hey, this isn't "Become a demon with me"!
三十路勧誘やめてやめて！
Stop trying to recruit me into turning thirty!
ならないよ！
We won't!
勢いすごいね。
Quite the momentum.
なったほうがいいけどね。ちょっとちゃんと間に入ってと。
It's better if you do, though. Let me just squeeze in between you two.
なんでよ！ぺこビビの空間...えー！
Why?! This is Peko-Bibi space... Ehh?!
ほらほらほら。
Come on, come on.
え、マリンちゃんね、そんなね、なんかまあずっとさ、ビビのさ、影響受けてみたいな、ぺこら先輩が。
Um, Marine-chan, like... Pekora-senpai being influenced by Bibi all this time...
ギャルってる？ギャルに影響受けてるよ。
Acting like a gyaru? She's definitely being influenced by a gyaru.
ウチ陰キャなの！ギャルにしないで、勝手に！
I'm an introvert! Don't just go turning me into a gyaru!
え、じゃあマリンちゃんの影響受けたらどうなるんやっけ？
Then what happens if she gets influenced by Marine-chan?
エッチになる。
She gets lewd.
なんでやねん！
Why would that happen?!
嫌だよ！
No way!
え、何でそれで嫌なんだよ！
Eh? Why are you disgusted by that?!
ホロライブこれ以上エッチなメンバー増えたらあかんだろ！てかね、そんなこと言いながら、
Hololive shouldn't have any more lewd members! Anyway, despite saying that...
でも、ちょっと待って、この状況楽しんでるよね？
But wait a minute, you're enjoying this situation, aren't you?
あ、え？楽しくねえし！
Ah, huh? I'm not enjoying it at all!
楽しそうだよ！
You look like you are!
楽しそうなんだよなー！
You totally look like you're having fun!
なんかさ、ビビをさ、こう挟むことによって二人の新しいシナジーみたいなさ、
Putting Bibi in between you two creates a new kind of synergy, like...
なんかこの何て言うの？あ、ね、ネット...あ、ダメかこれは。
What do you call this? Like a net... Ah, maybe not that.
何何何？
What, what, what?
いやいや、別にそんな...
No, no, not really...
7年...7年目？
Seven... The seventh year?
7年目。
The seventh year.
ま、7年もやってるとちょっと倦怠期みたいな...
Well, after 7 years, you hit a bit of a rut...
ありますからね。
That does happen.
え、でもぺこら最近マリンのさ、ええなところ増えた。
But lately, Pekora's found more things she likes about Marine.
え？
Eh?
え？ちょっと待って、はい？ちょっと待って、これビビの生誕祭なんですけど。
Huh? Wait, what? Hold on, this is Bibi's birthday festival!
これビビの生誕祭なんですけど！どういうこと？ちょっと待って、急に何ですか？ぺこら先輩、はい。
This is Bibi's birthday festival! What is this? Wait, where is this coming from all of a sudden, Pekora-senpai?
いやなんかー、やっぱさー、まあ元からねポテンシャルも高いし、マリンってもう今さ来ただけで空気変えてたやん、
Well, you know... She always had great potential, and Marine changed the whole vibe just by showing up,
ぺこビビの空気を。
shifting the Peko-Bibi vibe!
それ、そう...
That, yeah...
そう、それもあるけど、7年目にして気づいたの。
Yeah, that too, but in our seventh year, I realized something.
え、7年目にして？
In our seventh year?
ぺこらは、マリンの暴言が好きなの。
Pekora actually loves Marine's verbal abuse.
誰でもいいわけじゃないって！
It can't just be anyone, you know!
なんて奴だ！
What a menace!
このウサギ！このウサギめ！
This rabbit! Damn rabbit!
圧が足りないよ、そんな！そんな圧がない！
You're lacking pressure! There's no pressure in that!
もっと罵倒してほしいぺこ！
I want you to verbally abuse me more-peko!
やだー！
No way!
そんなんじゃない！
That's not how it works!
このウサギ！この三十路マリンちゃん！
This rabbit! This thirty-year-old Marine-chan!
なんて奴だ！なんて奴だ！
What a menace! What a menace!
今日誕生日ぺこなんだからさ、
Today is a birthday-peko, so...
でもさ、ビビちゃん前からさ、
But Bibi-chan, you've been saying for a while...
MVP、MVPって言ってたやん。
...about MVP, MVP.
そうだよね。
That's true.
だからさ、別にぺこマリでも、ぺこビビでもなく、
So instead of Peko-Mari or Peko-Bibi,
3人でMVPやればいいぺこじゃん。
why don't the three of us just do MVP-peko?
仲良くやろ。真ん中に、ほら真ん中にね。
Let's get along. In the middle, see, right in the middle.
なんかさ、うまいこと言って...
Saying something so smooth...
MVP！
MVP!
手でかいなお前意外と。
Your hand's surprisingly big.
確かに。
True.
そうなんだよ。あ、じゃあ両手に花でね！両手に花で！
That's right! Ah, then a flower in each hand! A flower in each hand!
ぺこマリ！イエーイ！
PekoMari! Yeah!
ねぇねぇ、いいじゃん！このメンバーでさ、なんか1曲やらない？
Hey, hey, isn't this great? Why don't the three of us do a song together?
いいじゃん！やろうぜ！
Sounds good! Let's do it!
待ってよ！
Wait a second!
なんか巻き込まれた気がするけど、でも嬉しい！
I feel like I got dragged into this, but I'm happy!
じゃあ、M3で歌っていいですか？
Then, can we perform for M3?
いいよー！
Go for it!
やったー！いっくぞー！
Yay! Here we go!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss."
今気づいた想い
These feelings I've just realized,
どんな言葉でも足りない
no words could ever be enough,
から
so...
1 2 3 4 !
1, 2, 3, 4!
当たり前すぎるくらい
It's almost too obvious,
友達の時間が長かったせいで
because we've spent so much time as friends.
あなたの癖や性格だって
Even your little habits and personality,
他の子より知ってんの
I know them better than any other girl.
意気地なしで 恥ずかしがり屋なあなたをもう
You're such a timid, shy coward that
待ってられないの！
I can't wait for you anymore!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss."
今更「好き」なんて
More than the words "I like you" after all this time,
言葉より 効き目あるでしょ？
it'll be far more effective, right?
あなたにだけは そっと教えてあげる
I'll softly reveal only to you
胸の奥 小さいつぼみのぬくもり
the warmth of the tiny flower bud deep within my chest.
時々甘えてみたり
Sometimes playing sweet,
拗ねてみたり そんな作戦らしくない
or sulking—tactics like that just aren't like me.
か弱きオトメじゃ勝てないの
Acting like a delicate maiden won't win you over.
この恋だけは負けらんない
This is the one love I cannot lose!
鈍感なあなたのこと 振り向かせたいから
Because I want to make an oblivious guy like you turn around,
勝負かけるの！
I'm making my move!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss."
「愛してます」なんて
More than the words "I love you,"
言葉より 魅力的でしょ？
wouldn't that be more charming?
聞こえちゃうくらい 速くなるドキドキ
My heartbeat races so fast you might even hear it.
初恋はサイダーみたいに弾ける
First love fizzes and pops just like cider!
“友達同士” そんな境界線
A borderline like "just friends"—
今すぐに 飛び越えたいの
I want to leap right over it this instant!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss."
今更「好き」なんて
More than the words "I like you" after all this time,
言葉より 効き目あるでしょ？
it'll be far more effective, right?
あなたにだけは そっと教えてあげる
I'll softly reveal only to you
胸の奥 小さいつぼみのぬくもり
the warmth of the tiny flower bud deep within my chest.
感じて
Feel it...
せーの
Ready, set...
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's just no good.
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
Look, that just won't work anymore.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will keep evolving, more and more!
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If put into words our relationship would vanish,
言葉を消せばいいやって 思ってた? 恐れてた?
did you think, "I should just erase my words"? Were you scared?
だけど あれ? なんか違うかも..
But wait, huh? Maybe something's not quite right...
千里の道も一歩から 石のようにかたいそんな意志で
A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step; with a resolve as solid as stone,
塵も積もればやまとなでしこ?
little by little, I'll become your ideal Japanese maiden?
「し」抜きで いや 死ぬ気で!
Without the "shi"... wait, with all I've got!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Soft and fluffy, fluttering around...
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Just you calling my name makes me float into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Fluttering around, soft and fluffy...
あなたが笑っている
Just you smiling
それだけで笑顔になる
is enough to make me smile.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's a trick of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
meeting you like this
しあわせなの
makes me so happy.
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's not good enough,
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
no, that's not it, see?
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart keeps evolving, more and more!
そう そんなんじゃ やだ
Right, I don't want it like that,
ねぇ そんなんじゃ まだ
hey, it's not enough yet!
私のこと見ててね
Keep watching me,
ずっとずっと
forever and always.
私の中のあなたほど
As much as you mean to me,
あなたの中の私の存在は
my presence inside your heart
まだまだ大きくないことも わかってるけれど
still isn't that big, I know, but...
今この同じ 瞬間
Right now, this very moment,
共有してる 実感
I feel that we are sharing it together.
塵も積もればやまとなでしこ?
Every little bit makes an ideal maiden?
略して ちりつもやまとなでこ!
In short: every little bit makes Nadeko!
くらくらり くらくらる
Dizzy and dazed, spinning around,
あなたを見上げたら それだけで眩しすぎて
just looking up at you is so dazzling,
くらくらる くらくらり
spinning around, dizzy and dazed,
あなたを想っている それだけで溶けてしまう
just thinking of you makes me melt away.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's a trick of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
meeting you like this
しあわせなの
makes me so happy.
コイスル キセツハ ヨクバリ circulation
A season in love is a greedy circulation.
コイスル キモチハ ヨクバリ circulation
Feelings in love are a greedy circulation.
コイスル ヒトミハ ヨクバリ circulation
Eyes in love are a greedy circulation.
コイスル オトメハ ヨクバリ circulation
A maiden in love is a greedy circulation.
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Light and fluffy, floating around,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
just you calling my name makes me float into space.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating around, light and fluffy,
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
just you smiling is enough to make me smile.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's a trick of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
meeting you like this
しあわせなの
makes me so happy.
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's not good enough,
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
no, that's not it, see?
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart keeps evolving, more and more!
そう そんなんじゃ やだ
Right, I don't want it like that,
ねぇ そんなんじゃ まだ
hey, it's not enough yet!
私のこと見ててね
Keep watching me,
ずっとずっと
forever and always.
chAngE なびかない 流されないよ
Change, I won't sway, I won't be swept away.
今 感じることに 素直でいたいの
I want to stay honest to what I feel right now.
chAngE 何度でも 生まれ変わるの
Change, I will be reborn again and again.
悲しみも抱きしめて 走り出すよ
Embracing even sadness, I'll start running.
タノシイ裏切りにあって とらわれない私がここにいるの
Faced with an amusing betrayal, an untamed me is standing here.
足りない 尽きない なんだってもっと歪ませてよ
Not enough, endless—go on, distort it all even more!
パターン化したこんな世界じゃ 自分が誰なのか分からなくなる
In a patterned world like this, I lose sight of who I am.
枠にはまりたくないわ 決めつけないでよ
I don't want to fit into a mold, don't define who I am.
道なき道を行くの
I'll blaze my own path.
そこにいたって 待っていたって 何も始まらない
Just standing there and waiting won't start a single thing.
chAngE なびかない 流されないよ
Change, I won't sway, I won't be swept away.
今 感じることに 素直でいたいの
I want to stay honest to what I feel right now.
誰かの思い通りにはさせないわ
I won't let anyone have their way with me.
chAngE 何度でも 生まれ変わるの
Change, I will be reborn again and again.
悲しみも抱きしめて 走り出すよ
Embracing even sadness, I'll start running.
あなたのもとには もう帰れないわ
I can never return to by your side again.
私は私らしく I wanna chAngE
True to myself, I wanna change.
なんでそんなためらって 満たされないあなたは何処にいるの？
Why hesitate so much? Where is the unfulfilled you?
消えない 錆びない 振りきって もっとハウらせてよ
It won't fade or rust; break through and make it feed back more.
変わったから気づく世界は 今のあたしを映してくれるでしょう
The world I notice now that I've changed will surely reflect who I am today.
あなたの思う未来は 何が映っているの？
In the future you envision, what do you see?
愛無き明日へ行くの
I'm heading toward a loveless tomorrow.
引き止めないで 恋しくたって あたしは進みたい
Don't hold me back; even if I miss it, I want to move forward.
chAngE 止まらない 振り向かないよ いつだって真実求めていたいの
Change; I won't stop, I won't look back, I always want to seek the truth.
涙も 愛おしく思える気がする
I feel like I can cherish even my tears.
もう chAngE 忘れない 無くしたくない 喜びも抱きしめて
Change; I won't forget, I don't want to lose it, embracing joy as well...
走り出すよ
...I'll start running.
あなたのもとから 離れてしまっても
Even if I stray far away from your side...
あたしはあたしらしく I wanna chAngE
...staying true to myself, I wanna change.
あたしが変わった先に あなたがいるなら
If you are there at the end of my change...
あなたが変わった先に あたしがいるなら
...and if I am there at the end of yours...
chAngE
走り出すよ
...I'll start running.
chAngE なびかない 流されないよ 今感じることに 素直でいたいの
Change; I won't sway, I won't be swept away, I want to stay true to what I feel now.
誰かの思い通りにはさせないわ
I won't let it just go the way someone else wants.
もう chAngE 何度でも 生まれ変わるの 悲しみも抱きしめて
Change; I'll be reborn again and again, embracing even sadness...
走り出すよ
...I'll start running.
ふたりで同じ景色が見れるなら
If the two of us can see the same scenery...
あなたのもとにいつか帰りたいわ
...I want to return to your side someday.
あたしはあたしらしく I wanna chAngE
Staying true to myself, I wanna change.
あのね
You know...
I say 私、大丈夫？
I say, "Am I okay?"
Maybe, 上手くやれるはず ずっと走った 息継ぎもしないまま
Maybe, I should be able to do it, running all this time without even catching my breath.
あっそ、終わりが来るなら 別に寂しくなんかない
Oh well, if the end is coming, I'm not really lonely at all.
真実は心の奥の方
The truth is deep within my heart.
自分のことすら愛せないまま 君のこと守れるのかな
Without even being able to love myself, I wonder if I can protect you.
信じて
"Believe in me."
どうか、正真正銘のこの思いを
Please, listen to these genuine feelings of mine,
聴いて 私、全身全霊で歌うから
because I will sing with all my body and soul.
大丈夫、世界はこんなに綺麗だと
It's okay, I'll show you the world is so beautiful...
分かってる 分かってる 分かってる... わかってるよ！
I know, I know, I get it... I know!
ごめんね じれったい 足りない こんなんじゃ誰も愛せないの
I'm sorry, it's frustrating, not enough; I can't love anyone like this.
止めない 止まることは知らないの
I won't stop, I don't know how to stop.
言葉足らず 失くしてしまう物ばかりだ
Lacking words, all I do is lose things.
Luna say maybe...
降るのは
What falls is...
迷be, rainy
...maybe rainy.
愛せ、どんな自分でも Navy色に染まるまで
Love whatever self you are, until dyed in navy.
時間はかかるかもしれないけど
It might take time, but...
I know, 輝くしかないこと ハイライト、塗り続けるしかない
I know there's no choice but to shine, no choice but to keep painting highlights.
真実はちゃんと 言わなくちゃね
I have to speak the truth properly, don't I?
目に見えるものが
The things visible to the eye...
続く、ずっと
...will continue forever,
そう、ずっと
yes, forever,
思いたい
is what I want to believe.
君に、半信半疑な素振りして
Acting doubtful towards you,
心、空回り、遠回り
my heart spins in circles, taking the long way around.
最低だ、もう一回やり直せるのなら
It's pathetic; if I could start over just once more,
素直になりたい、なりたい、なりたいと
I want to be honest, want to be, want to be,
願ったジレンマ
a dilemma I wished for.
このまま、1人じゃ何もできない
Like this, I can't do anything alone,
全部、決めるのは
deciding everything is...
決めるのは自分次第
Deciding is up to me.
初めて背中を見たときに 覚悟決めた
When I first saw your back, I steeled my resolve.
どこまで行けるのか
Just how far can I go?
届くのか
Will it reach?
分からないよ
I don't even know.
臆病がそこに立っている
Cowardice is standing right there.
3秒前バックステージ 震える背中を君に預けて
3 seconds before backstage, entrusting my trembling back to you,
この運命的出逢いは
this fateful encounter is...
そう きっと 偶然みたいな
Yeah, surely, like a coincidence,
多分 神様の悪戯です
maybe it's a prank of God.
どうか 真正銘のこの想いが 君のところにちゃんと届くまで
Please, until these genuine feelings of mine properly reach your heart,
ここで私 全身全霊で歌うから
I will sing right here with all my body and soul!
待ってる 待ってる だからこの場所大切にしたいの
Waiting, waiting, so I want to cherish this place!
これが 真正銘の私だ
This is the genuine me!
大丈夫 もう怖くはないわ
It's alright, I'm not scared anymore.
たまに躓くことなら あるけれど
Though I might stumble every once in a while,
1番特等席で君の笑顔見たいんだ 私だけの特権
I want to see your smile from the best seat—it's my special privilege.
見えない未来 手探り 今日もステージの上で
An invisible future, groping in the dark—today too, on stage,
証明してみせるから
I will prove it to you!
ここにしかないスクリーン
A screen that exists only here.
君にまだ話せてないことばかりあるんだ 聴いてほしいの
There are so many things I haven't told you yet, I want you to hear them.
あのね...
You know...
みんなー！
Everyone—!
ありがとうございますー！
Thank you so much!
え、皆さん楽しんでくれてますかー？
Um, is everyone having fun?!
うわー！ずっとね、コメントもたくさん見えてます。
Whoa! I've been seeing tons of your comments the whole time.
みんな盛り上げてくださって、ありがとうー！
Thank you all for hyping things up!
はい！ということでですね、ライブも終盤になっているんですけれども、
Alright! So, the concert is approaching its final stretch, but...
なんか先ほどスタッフさんにですね、トレンド1位だとお聞きしましたー！
The staff just told me earlier that we reached number one on trending!
え、またトレンド1位？！えー！ヴィヴィ生誕祭2026、みんなポストしてくれてありがとうー！
Eh, #1 on trending again?! Yay! Thank you everyone for posting with #ヴィヴィ生誕祭2026!
そして、とんでもないことに一瞬「いやらしい」もトレンド入りしたみたいです。
And crazy enough, it seems "lewd" briefly trended too.
トレンド入りするな、かい！え、ヴィヴィ今年「ラッキーキー」を流行らせていきたいって言ってたのに、「ラッキーキー」より「いやらしい」の方が流行ってしまってるかな？
Don't let that trend! Vivi said she wanted "Lucky Key" to catch on this year, but did "lewd" trend more than "Lucky Key"?
はい。いや、でも皆さんのおかげです！本当にありがとうございますー！
Yes. But really, it's all thanks to you guys! Thank you so very much!
はい！次がですね、最後の曲になるんですが、
Alright! The next song will be our final song,
えーなんと、ヴィヴィの...初めての！オリジナル楽曲を披露したいと思いますー！
and amazingly, I will be performing... Vivi's very first... original song!
やったー！やっと皆さんにお届けできます！
Yay! I can finally deliver it to all of you!
タイトルは「ビビッドキュート」です！
The title is "Vivid Cute"!
ということで、この後披露させていただきます！
So with that said, I'll perform it right now!
じゃあ一旦ちょっと準備してくるね。お水飲んでくるわ。待ってて！
I'm gonna go get ready for a moment. Gonna grab some water. Wait for me!
鮮やか変身メイクアップ
A vivid transformation makeup!
超ヴィヴィっとくるっしょ？ (ビビッドキュート)
It strikes you super Vivi-dly, right? (Vivid Cute)
アップデート順調！ (ビビッドキュート)
Update progressing smoothly! (Vivid Cute)
超ヴィヴィっとくるっしょ？ (ビビッドキュート)
It strikes you super Vivi-dly, right? (Vivid Cute)
アップデート順調！
Update progressing smoothly!
なりたい自分 変幻自在
The self I want to become, ever-changing and free,
悩まないショッピング 直感でポチッと！
shopping without hesitation, clicking "buy" on pure instinct!
案外単純なことで 気分も未来もアガるの
Through surprisingly simple things, both my mood and my future soar!
世界平和に比べりゃ 私の前髪とか
Compared to world peace, something like my bangs...
微々たるもんだけど こっちのが大事！ (大事！)
...is minuscule, but this matters much more to me! (More!)
好きな自分は 好きに自分でつくるので
Because I create the self I like however I like,
カラフルデコレーション テンション ねえかわいい？
colorful decoration, soaring tension—hey, am I cute?
憧れ真似して 自分色へ
Imitating my idols, blending into my own colors,
鏡の前でセルフィー 街中どこだってランウェイ
a selfie in front of the mirror, turning the whole city into a runway!
ビビッドにキュートに 変身...
Vividly and cutely transforming...
Come on!
トレンドしたい！
Wanna be on trend!
セール狙って爆買い
Going on a shopping spree at the sales,
トレンドしない？
shouldn't I follow trends?
欲張り少し後悔
Regretting being a bit too greedy...
トレンドしたい！
Wanna be on trend!
けどしっくりくる自分がいい
But being true to myself feels best!
あっちこっちのリアル
Real life everywhere...
差し色ひとつでも
Even just a single accent color
こんなに変わるのに
can change everything so much,
何もしないなんてのはもったいない
so doing nothing would be such a waste!
思いつくまま 試すのです
Just try whatever comes to mind!
ト・レ・ン・ド ビビッとキュート
Trend! Vivid Cute!
目の覚めるような
Even if it's not
ビフォーアフターじゃなくても
an eye-popping before-and-after,
君が気づいてくれたら大成功
if you notice it, it's a total success!
1秒前の自分の決心を褒めましょう
Let's praise ourselves for the decision we made a second ago!
ビビッドに色付くの毎日が
My everyday life is colored vividly,
キュートな音色も聞こえてきて
and I can hear cute melodies echoing.
魔法少女のようなシチュエーション
It's a situation just like a magical girl!
「好き」の気持ちで何にでもなれるの
With feelings of "love," I can become anything!
カラフルデコレーション 超ね、可愛い？
Colorful decoration, isn't it super cute?
憧れ真似して 自分色へ
Copying my inspirations, making it my own color.
鏡の前でセルフィー
Taking a selfie in front of the mirror,
街中どこだってランウェイ
the whole town is my runway!
ビビッドにキュートに
Vividly and cutely,
変身メイクアップ！
transformation make-up!
ピンクのリップでスキップ 街も色付いていく
Skipping along with pink lip gloss, the town colors up too.
ピンクのリップでスキップ なりたい自分へと
Skipping along with pink lip gloss, towards the me I want to be!
もっともっとメイクアップ ビビッドキュート
More and more make-up! Vivid Cute!
超ヴィヴィっとくるっしょ？
It strikes a chord super Vivi-dly, right?
アップデート順調！
Update going smoothly!
超ヴィヴィっとくるっしょ？
It strikes a chord super Vivi-dly, right?
アップデート順調！
Update going smoothly!
緊張したー！
I was so nervous!
お水飲んできます！
I'm gonna go grab some water!
よっこ... ただいまー！
Oof... I'm back~!
みんなー！ヴィヴィの初めてのオリジナルソロ曲、
Everyone! Vivi's very first original solo song,
『ビビッドキュート』聴いていただきましたー！
"Vivid Cute," you just listened to it!
どうやったー？
How was it?
ん？よかった？可愛い？
Hmm? Was it good? Cute?
知ってるー！
I know, right!
やったー！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
ということで、ちょっと新曲について詳しくご紹介したいなと思います！
So with that, I'd like to tell you a bit more about the new song!
改めてタイトルは、『ビビッドキュート』です！
Once again, the title is "Vivid Cute"!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
うわー！なんだこの美少女！
Whoa! Who is this beautiful girl?!
あ、ヴィヴィやった！可愛すぎて一瞬誰かわからんかった！
Ah, it was Vivi! It was so cute I didn't recognize myself for a second!
はい、ま、いつも可愛いですけどもね！はい！
Well, I'm always cute though! Yes!
えーこちらですね、可愛い女の子が
So this song is about a cute girl
コスメで変身するような可愛い気持ちを歌にした楽曲になっておりますー！
transforming with cosmetics, putting those lovely feelings into a song!
はい、ま、ヴィヴィといえばメイク担当ですから、
Yes, well, when you think of Vivi, I'm in charge of makeup,
そのときのワクワク感をね、思い出しながら歌っています！
so I sang it while remembering that thrilling excitement!
で、ミュージックビデオも作成中なので、また告知するから待っててねー！
Also, the music video is in production, so please look forward to the announcement!
そして！音源リリースは、本日24時からになりますー！
And! The digital release will be available today from midnight!
みんな、たくさん聴いてなー！
Everyone, please listen to it a lot, okay!
はい、そしてー！
Yes, and next!
皆さんお待ちかねー！
What you've all been waiting for!
綺々羅ヴィヴィ 誕生日記念2026グッズが発売されますー！
Kikirara Vivi Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise is going on sale!
はーい、可愛いー！
Yay, so cute!
ちょっとじゃあ早速一つ一つ見ていきましょう！
Alright then, let's take a look at each of them right away!
一つ目はこちら！
The first item is this!
「ヴィヴィとおやすみ抱き枕カバー」！
"Sleep with Vivi Body Pillow Cover"!
え、なんか、え、これこそ、いやらしい... いやらしいでしょ、ね？
Uh, isn't this... like, really risqué? It is, right?
ヴィヴィ初の抱き枕カバーでーす！
It's Vivi's very first body pillow cover!
イラストはnoncoママに描いてもらいました。
The illustration was drawn by nonco-mama.
気分に合わせて裏表で使ってください！
Please use either the front or back depending on your mood!
二つ目はこちら！
The second item is this!
「ヴィヴィのめちゃかわ缶バッジ」！
"Vivi's Super Cute Can Badge"!
今回のnoncoママのイラストを使った缶バッジです！
It's a can badge featuring nonco-mama's illustration!
えーなんか、ね、ヴィヴィってこんな表情もできるんやー。可愛い！
Like, wow, Vivi can make this kind of expression too! So cute!
色んな所に付けて、ヴィヴィとアピールしちゃってください！
Attach it to various places and show off your love for Vivi!
ぜひ痛バッグも作ってねー！
Definitely make an itabag with it too!
三つ目はこちら！
The third item is this!
「ちぃヴィヴィぬいぐるみキーホルダー」！
"Chibi Vivi Plush Keychain"!
はい、このね、ちぃヴィヴィついに、ついにグッズ化となりましたー！
Yes, this Chibi Vivi has finally, finally become official merchandise!
猫着ぐるみを着たちぃヴィヴィになってます。
It's Chibi Vivi wearing a cat kigurumi suit.
色んな所に付けてたくさん可愛がってくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you attach it everywhere and love it lots!
ヴィヴィのね、他のキーホルダーとかと並べて付けても絶対可愛いです！
It'll definitely be super cute even lined up with Vivi's other keychains!
四つ目はこちら！
The fourth item is this!
「ヴィヴィとおそろい推し活バッグ」！
"Matching Oshikatsu Bag with Vivi"!
ヴィヴィがいつも持ってるバッグをイメージした推し活用バッグです！
It's an oshikatsu bag modeled after the bag Vivi always carries!
こっちはぬいぐるみを 入れて持ち歩いてくださーい！
Put plushies in here and carry them around with you!
わー可愛い！ビビとお揃いしよ？
Wow, so cute! Match with Vivi, okay?
そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the full-set purchase bonus!
チェキ風ブロマイドカード！
Instax-style bromide card!
こちらをですね、ビビの直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージが入ってます！
This comes with Vivi's handwritten autograph and a foil-stamped printed message!
メッセージの内容は届いてからのお・た・の・し・み♡
The content of the message is a surprise for when it arrives!
さらに特典ボイスもつきます！
In addition, you also get a bonus voice pack!
タイトルは「ベッドで一緒にゴロゴロしよー？」
The title is: "Wanna laze around in bed together?"
です！ビビと2人でベッドで一緒にゴロゴロしている気持ちになれるシチュエーションボイスになってます！
Yes! It's a situation voice track where you can feel like you're lazing around in bed together with Vivi!
みんなこれは絶対聴かないと！
Everyone, you definitely have to listen to this!
さあ、ここまで新曲告知とグッズ紹介でしたー！
Well, that's all for the new song announcement and merchandise intro!
この後はメン限もあるからみんな、ぜーったいぜーったい遊びに来てね！
There's a members-only stream after this, so everyone, definitely, definitely come hang out!
何をやるかはまだ、お楽しみにー！
What we'll be doing is still a surprise!
ぜひ、まだの方はチャンネル登録と通知をオンにして、
If you haven't yet, please subscribe and turn on notifications,
メン限の方にも入っていただきアンコールも一緒に楽しめればと思います！
join the membership, and enjoy the encore together!
ということで、ここまでお知らせを一気にダダッとお知らせさせていただいたんですけども、
And with that, I rattled through all those announcements in one go, but...
こうして、えー、初めてのね、生誕3Dライブを迎えることができたのも、
being able to hold my very first 3D Birthday Live like this...
本当に、いつも応援してくださっている皆さんのおかげです！
is truly all thanks to everyone who is always supporting me!
日々ビビが活動できているのは、vividの支えがあるからです！
The reason Vivi can keep going day after day is because of vivid's support!
そして、改めてですね、この生誕祭、もう準備期間結構ちょっと長かったんですけど、
And also, the prep time for this birthday festival was actually pretty long,
そんな中、ずっと支えてくださって協力してくれた、尽力してくださったスタッフの皆さんも本当にありがとうございます！
but to all the staff members who supported, cooperated, and worked so hard the whole time, thank you so very much!
こうやってたくさんね、支えてくださるスタッフの皆さんと、そしてゲストで出てくださった、
To all the staff who supported me so much, and the guests who appeared...
出てくださったホロメンの皆さんや、いつも仲良くしてくださってるホロメンの皆さんや、
all the Holomems who appeared and are always so nice to me,
そして、こうして今配信を見てくださっているそこのあなた！の存在が、
and to each and every one of you watching this stream right now,
今のビビの背中を押してくださってます！本当にいつもありがとうございます！
your presence is what keeps pushing Vivi forward! Thank you so much, as always!
なんかちょっと言葉で伝えるの下手くそなんですが、みんなの応援があるからビビはこれからも、
I'm not very good at putting this into words, but with everyone's support, Vivi will...
どんどん、どんどん階段を登っていきたいと思いまーす！
keep climbing up the stairs step by step from now on!
みんなずっとずっとついてきてよー！
Everyone, please stay by my side forever and ever!
それでは！メン限でお会いしましょう！
Alright then! See you in the members-only stream!
せーの、うー、ビビー！
Ready, set... Ooh, Vivi!
またねー！
See ya!
[画面の文字] 大好きなvividへ♡ 緊張で震える膝、支えてくれてありがとう！ みんながヴィヴィをアイドルにしてくれたよ！ どんな困難でもみんながいれば乗り越えていける！！ これからもずっとそばにいて♡
[On-screen] "To my beloved vivid♡ Thank you for supporting my trembling knees! You all made Vivi an idol! As long as I have you all, I can overcome any hardship!! Please stay by my side forever♡"